



Jayesh Manani

Nationality: Indian

(+49) 17674882019

Gender: Male

☑ Email address: jsmanani@gmail.com

Website: https://jayeshmanani.github.io/

Skype: jayeshmanani

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mananijayesh/

• Address: Allmandring 1 B10 - Zimmernummer - 11, 70569 Stuttgart (Germany)

ABOUT ME

I am a skilled, determined and active individual, with broad skills and experience as a software developer, and handling small to large projects. I use Python, and Javascript to build software, web apps, scripts, and scrapers. Furthermore, I am adept at handling multiple tasks on a daily basis competently and at working well under pressure. A key strength is to write an algorithm, build efficient, clean and reliable software code, and design software. Recently, I have worked as a software engineer and research associate at one of the prestigious management institutes Globally, the Indian Institute of Management, Ahmedabad.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software developer

Sameeksha Capital [13/10/2020 - 03/03/2022]

City: Ahmedabad Country: India

Working as a Python Developer.

Responsibilities:

- Write effective, scalable code
- Develop back-end components to improve responsiveness and overall performance.
- Upgrade software with new feature in Django and Flask based web app (In-house trading software)
- Integrate user-facing elements into applications
- Test and debug programs
- Improve functionality of existing systems
- Implement security and data protection solutions
- Assess and prioritize feature requests
- Coordinate with internal teams to understand user requirements and provide technical solutions
- Manage Google Cloud (App Engine, SQL, Cloud Functions, Compute Engine)
- Version controlling using git
- Database development and Maintainance
- Build various web scraping scripts
- Build various tools for data analysis and automation
- Automate daily routine process which can save our daily time

Research Associate

Indian Institute of Management, Ahmedabad [22/07/2019 - 30/11/2020]

City: Ahmedabad Country: India

At IIM Ahmedabad I used to help the Prof. Samrat Gupta and Prof. Sanket Mohapatra in the research work, To collect the data for the research work, to perform the various test on the data, to run the some of the algorithm in the research work and much more things that I get to learn at IIM Ahmedabad.

At IIM Ahmedabad I also learned about many new algorithms, soft computing methods, community detection in social network and other networks using soft computing. Explored how research work can be done, tools that are being used during the work of research and much more to go.

At IIM Ahmedabad I have also worked on the project which consists of the development of the GUI based interface which fetches the data from various 17 API's of the variables from IMF (INTERNATIONAL MONETARY FUND) and World bank databases and automates the collection of the data on the timely basis, and also, we can filter the data by country, time and variables.

Software Engineer

Allevents.in [16/01/2019 - 17/07/2019]

City: Ahmedabad Country: India

Worked as Data Science and Machine Learning Engineer.

Find useful insight from the Past and upcoming text data which can be helpful for finding the Trends in the Advance.

Worked on the clustering the user based on their past usage of the event making. Which helps in targeted marketing for the promotion of some paid features

Working on text multi-label, hierarchical classification using the Machine Learning approaches which classifies the particular text into a particular hierarchy of category.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

IBM Data Science Specialization

Coursera [01/01/2020 - 28/01/2020]

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/certificate/K3DPYU77F75F

Bachelor of Engineering

L.D. College of Engineering, Gujarat Technological University, Ahmedabad [01/08/2014 - 01/01/2019]

Address: LD College of Engineering, 120 Circular Road, University Area, 380015 Ahmedabad (India)

http://ldce.ac.in/

Field(s) of study: Information and Communication Technologies : *Software and applications development and analysis Computer use Database and network design and administration*

Final grade: 7.6

https://github.com/jayeshmanani/RTIInfo-Portal https://jayeshmanani.github.io/

Projects:

- RTIInfo-Portal: As part of our final year project we have built this efficient web app to solve the problem of redundancy and use the sharing economy concept to share the common information. This is the complete PHP project with all working. You can find code for login with google, convert inputs to a predefined pdf file, saving data of the new users to the database, upload the files to the server and save its path to the database, find the files from the server and display it in the page, and much more.
- Online Blood Bank: As part of our design engineering subject for 2 years (in 3rd, 4th, 5th and 6th Semester). This is the project where we have built a POC (Proof of concept) for making an online app from where we can provide the service related to the blood-related issues and events, like Nearby upcoming blood donation camps, this blood is available in this area, one can request for the kind of blood (for various blood groups), So, one who is in the nearby area can reach out to the needful and help the people out there.

Masters of Science

University of Stuttgart [01/04/2022 - Current]

Address: Pfaffenwaldring, 70569 Stuttgart (Germany)

https://www.uni-stuttgart.de/

Field(s) of study: Information and Communication Technologies

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Gujarati

Other language(s):

Hindi English

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2 LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2 SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

DIGITAL SKILLS

Organizational and planning skills / Good listener and communicator / Written and Verbal skills / Decision-making / Conflict resolution / Presenting / Analytical skills / Motivated / Team-work oriented / Critical thinking / Strategic Planning / Research and analytical skills / Creativity / Data analysis / Microsoft Office / Responsibility / Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, Access, Power Point, Outlook.